<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://www.fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>NYS Office of Information Technology Services, GIS Program Office</origin>
				<pubdate>20131007</pubdate>
				<title>Orange County Ortho 4 bd 24in</title>
				<geoform>raster digital data</geoform>
				<serinfo>
					<sername>NYS Digital Ortho-imagery Program (NYSDOP)</sername>
					<issue>2013 imagery in Orange County</issue>
				</serinfo>
				<pubinfo>
					<pubplace>Albany, New York</pubplace>
					<publish>NYS Office of Information Technology Services, GIS Program Office</publish>
				</pubinfo>
			</citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<abstract>These files contain 2013 digital Ortho-imagery of Orange County, New York. Image pixel size is 2' GSD. Image type is 4-band, RGB &amp; NIR. T  Image horizontal accuracy is within 4' at the 95% confidence level (NSSDA). Each file contains an image covering 4000 ft. by 6000 ft. on the ground.</abstract>
			<purpose>This digital Ortho-imagery can serve a variety of purposes, from general planning to field reference for spatial analysis to a tool for revision of vector maps. It can also serve as a reference layer for GIS.</purpose>
		</descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<sngdate>
					<caldate>20130506</caldate>
				</sngdate>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>ground condition</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>Complete</progress>
			<update>Irregular</update>
		</status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc>
-74.763858</westbc>
				<eastbc>
-74.083409</eastbc>
				<northbc>
41.138707</northbc>
				<southbc>
41.633496</southbc>
			</bounding>
		</spdom>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekt>Orthophoto, ortho</themekt>
				<themekey>Digital Ortho-imagery</themekey>
			</theme>
			<place>
				<placekt>none</placekt>
				<placekey> Orange County</placekey>
				<placekey>New York</placekey>
			</place>
		</keywords>
		<accconst>Some imagery tiles are classified as sensitive due to their content.</accconst>
		<useconst>Use of sensitive imagery, if granted, is only for the use specified in the request.</useconst>
		<ptcontac>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntperp>
					<cntper>Tim Ruhren</cntper>
					<cntorg>NYS ITS GIS Program Office</cntorg>
				</cntperp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
					<address>tate Office Campus Building 7A, 4th Floor, 1220 Washington Avenue</address>
					<city>Albany</city>
					<state>New York</state>
					<postal>12242</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>518-242-5029</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>518-322-4976</cntfax>
				<cntemail>truhren@dhses.ny.gov</cntemail>
				<hours>9am -4:30pm Easten time</hours>
			</cntinfo>
		</ptcontac>
		<datacred>NYS ITS GIS Progam Office</datacred>
		<secinfo>
		</secinfo>
		<native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.1850</native>
	</idinfo>
	<dataqual>
		<logic>The dataset contains raster images or digital ortho images so the logical consistency report is not applicable. The file naming convention was supplied by New York State. When the ortho tiles were created the file names were restricted to a numeric value representing the lower left corner of the ortho tile. These tiles were then all renamed using a batch script so that they reflected the N.Y. state standard (i.e. "c_10470162_12_09600_4bd_2009.tif"). Consistency of file naming was ensured by using a batch process. The file naming convention consists of the first letter for Central, East, West or Long Island for New York State Plane Coordinate Systems (NYSPCS). The following four numeric characters represent the first four characters of the "X" coordinate value for the tile's lower left corner coordinate in NYSPCS and the next four characters represent the first four characters of the "Y" coordinate value for the tile's lower left corner coordinate in NYSPCS. The next two numeric characters represent the tile's Ground Sampling Distance (GSD) value in ft. The following five numeric characters represent the Above Mean Terrain (AMT) nominal height at which the DMC sensor recorded or collected the original imagery for the corresponding area. The next three characters are "4bd" for 4-band ortho-photos. Lastly, the last four numeric digits represent the year in which the particular ortho was created.</logic>
		<complete>The project consisted of 737 final tiles.</complete>
		<lineage>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>The Digital Natural Color aerial imagery was acquired in Spring 2013 using a DMC sensor flown at a nominal height of 19200' AMT (Above Mean Terrain). ABGPS data was also collected and processed using POSPac  (version 5.1) Mobile Mapping Suite .  The Ground Control used to support the 4-band ortho-imagery production was collected by identifying strategic points on previous aerial photography and supplemented by selecting new points or photo identifiable points (PID) in areas where needed due to a lack or minimal existence of points from previous ortho-imagery production projects and then determining the precise location coordinates of the entire ground control network by using ground survey techniques. The new Ground Control Network was also supplemented by targeting existing New York State HARN stations data. The Digital Aerial Triangulation (DAT) was performed, primarily, using softcopy workstations and Intergraph's ISAT. DAT solutions were independently reviewed and checked using independent blind control points. Digital Elevation Models (DEM) (mass-points and break-lines) used to support ortho imagery production were supplied by the state and updated using standard photogrammetric collection techniques on Intergraph soft copy workstations.  The images were then ortho-rectified using Sanborn's proprietary APS orthophoto software modules. Color balancing, seamless mosaicking was performed by automatic and manual seam line creation steps, final color balancing and final extractions were also accomplished using this software. A final tile by tile quality control was performed using Adobe PhotoShop software.  The imagery product deliverables are GeoTIFF images with embedded header information describing the required projection, pixel size, tile size and other related data and corresponding world files (.tfw).  Derivative compressed imagery is also available in JP2000 format.</procdesc>
				<procdate>Unknown</procdate>
				<srcprod>Aerial Imagery</srcprod>
				<proccont>
					<cntinfo>
						<cntperp>
							<cntper>Shawn Benham</cntper>
							<cntorg>Sanborn Map Company Inc.</cntorg>
						</cntperp>
						<cntpos>Project Manager</cntpos>
						<cntaddr>
							<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
							<address>1935 Jamboree Drive, Suite 100</address>
							<city>Colorado Springs</city>
							<state>Colorado</state>
							<postal>80920</postal>
							<country>USA</country>
						</cntaddr>
						<cntvoice>719-502-1296</cntvoice>
						<cntemail>sbenham@sanborn.com</cntemail>
						<hours>9am - 5pm Eastern Time</hours>
					</cntinfo>
				</proccont>
			</procstep>
		</lineage>
		<cloud>&lt;1%</cloud>
		<posacc><horizpa><horizpar>+/-8 ft. at the 95% confidence level (NSSDA) for 24 inch resolution.</horizpar></horizpa></posacc></dataqual>
	<spdoinfo>
		<direct>Raster</direct>
		<rastinfo>
		</rastinfo>
	</spdoinfo>
	<spref>
		<horizsys>
			<planar>
				<mapproj>
					<mapprojn>Transverse Mercator</mapprojn>
					<transmer>
						<sfctrmer>0.999900</sfctrmer>
						<longcm>-74.500000</longcm>
						<latprjo>38.833333</latprjo>
						<feast>492125.000000</feast>
						<fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
					</transmer>
				</mapproj>
				<planci>
					<plance>coordinate pair</plance>
					<coordrep>
						<absres>0.000000</absres>
						<ordres>0.000000</ordres>
					</coordrep>
					<plandu>survey feet</plandu>
				</planci>
			</planar>
			<geodetic>
				<horizdn>D_North_American_1983</horizdn>
				<ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
				<semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
				<denflat>298.257222</denflat>
			</geodetic>
			<cordsysn><geogcsn>GCS_North_American_1983</geogcsn><projcsn>NAD_1983_StatePlane_New_York_East_FIPS_3101_Feet</projcsn></cordsysn></horizsys>
	</spref>
	<eainfo>
	</eainfo>
	<distinfo>
		<resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
		<stdorder>
			<digform>
				<digtinfo>
					<transize>0.004</transize>
				</digtinfo>
			</digform>
		</stdorder>
	</distinfo>
	<metainfo>
		<metd>20131007</metd>
		<metc>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntperp>
					<cntper>Tim Ruhren</cntper>
					<cntorg>NYS ITS GIS Program Office</cntorg>
				</cntperp>
				<cntpos>NYS GIS Clearinghouse</cntpos>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
					<address>State Office Campus Building 7A, 4th Floor, 1220 Washington Avenue</address>
					<city>Albany</city>
					<state>New York</state>
					<postal>12242</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>518-242-5029</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>518-322-4976</cntfax>
				<cntemail>truhren@dhses.ny.gov</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</metc>
		<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
		<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
		<mettc>local time</mettc>
	</metainfo>
	<Esri><ModDate>20131007</ModDate><ModTime>11571600</ModTime></Esri><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20131007</mdDateSt></metadata>
